<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-07-22T16:21:42-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Open Education Analytics</title><subtitle>Open Education Analytics (OEA) is a fully open-sourced data integration and analytics architecture and reference implementation for the education sector built on Synapse Analytics - with Azure Data Lake Storage as the storage backbone, and Azure Active Directory as providing the role-based access control.</subtitle><author><name>Gene Garcia</name></author><entry><title type="html">OEA Overview</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Overview/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OEA Overview" /><published>2021-05-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-05-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Overview</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/Overview/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;open-education-analytics-overview&quot;&gt;Open Education Analytics Overview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amount of innovation that has been occuring in the data engineering and data science space - across all industries - in the past 5-10 years has been tremendous. A paradigm shift has been occuring and will continue to accelerate as ever more powerful and more accessible data services continue to roll out. OEA is focused on getting the word out about how to effectively setup and manage a modern data estate, and we’re working to build up a community of customers and partners that openly share core components/modules built on a reference architecture. The goal is to allow us as an industry to move past the low-level challenges of basic data centralization, data prep, data analysis, and data interoperability so we can put more time and energy into solving the deeper challenges. To properly serve the students, teachers, and administrators who are relying on us (“us” being the global edtech community), we’ve got to get to a place where the competition and product differentiation occurs well above the basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been a goal in the edtech world for a long time - so what has changed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;products offer better API’s&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;edu orgs recognize the power of the cloud (more willing to use the cloud)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;standards have evolved further (a little); the need/desire for convergence has grown; some amount of disillusionment with standards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;open source communities greatly facilitated by Github (and embraced by large companies, especially platform companies)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;data engineering and analytics tech is the real game-changer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, there have been modest developments in standards&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gene Garcia</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="oea" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Open Education Analytics Overview The amount of innovation that has been occuring in the data engineering and data science space - across all industries - in the past 5-10 years has been tremendous. A paradigm shift has been occuring and will continue to accelerate as ever more powerful and more accessible data services continue to roll out. OEA is focused on getting the word out about how to effectively setup and manage a modern data estate, and we’re working to build up a community of customers and partners that openly share core components/modules built on a reference architecture. The goal is to allow us as an industry to move past the low-level challenges of basic data centralization, data prep, data analysis, and data interoperability so we can put more time and energy into solving the deeper challenges. To properly serve the students, teachers, and administrators who are relying on us (“us” being the global edtech community), we’ve got to get to a place where the competition and product differentiation occurs well above the basics.</summary></entry></feed>